我叫小鬼。
My name is Gudo.
我曾经是一名灵魂守护者。
I used to be a Soul Keeper.
我的工作是护送
My job was to escort
刚刚逝去的灵魂前往转世之地。
newly deceased souls to their rebirth.
但后来，我的职责发生了变化。
But my duty changed later on.
每一位逝去的灵魂都会被指派一名灵魂守护者。
Every departed soul is assigned a Soul Keeper.
当他们终于能够放下尘世牵挂，
When they can finally let go of the human world,
将双手交托给我们时……
with their hands in ours...
我们会引领他们沿着湖畔前往米山。
we shepherd them along the lake to Mount Mi.
在那里，他们将留下自己的记忆。
There, they will leave their memories behind.
当他们穿过瀑布……
After they pass through the waterfall...
便会转世重生。
They will be reincarnated.
瀑布会冲走他们灵魂的大部分。
The waterfall washes away much of their souls.
剩下的部分会化作一根绳索。
What remains will transform into a rope.
绳索上通常会有结。
There are usually knots on the rope.
这些结代表着他们一生中未解的怨恨。
These knots represent their life's unresolved resentments.
我不知道什么是“未解的怨恨”，
I don't know what "unresolved resentments" are,
但我知道它们会积聚成邪恶的种子。
but I do know that they accumulate into seeds of evil.
这些种子潜藏在他们的体内，
The seeds hide inside their bodies
直到被愤怒与仇恨释放出来。
until they are unleashed by rage and hatred.
将人类变成可怕的“愤怒”……
Turning humans into terrifying Wraths...
送我回去，他需要我！
Send me back, he needs me!
但我认为人类比这更复杂。
But I think humans are more complicated than that.
邪恶的种子未必会毁灭他们。
Seeds of evil won't necessarily destroy them.
它们甚至可能推动人类生存下去。
They may even push humans to survive.
请问……
Excuse me...
你见过一个大概这么高的小孩吗？
Have you seen a little kid about this tall?
没有。
No.
我和弟弟走散了，你能帮帮我吗？
My brother and I got separated, can you help me?
弟弟？
Brother?
为什么你们不能就这样分开呢？
Why can't you just stay separated?
因为他是我的弟弟啊！
Because he's my little brother!
他和我一样有一头绿发，而且他……
He's got green hair like me, and he...
有一天，我遇见了一个名叫小妹的女孩。
One day, I met a girl named Yuri.
她并不知道自己已经去世，
Not realizing she has died,
却坚持要寻找走失的弟弟。
she insisted on finding her lost brother.
好吧，我会陪你一起寻找。
Okay, I'll join you on your search.
不好意思，让一让。
Excuse me, coming through.
她怎么会在这里露面？
Why is she showing her face here?
嘘！她会听见我们的！
Shh! She'll hear us!
父亲！
Father!
莫克将军，怎么只有您一个人？我父亲在哪里？
General Mok, why is it only you? Where is my father?
国王驾崩了，国王万岁！
The King is dead, long live the King!
国王是在战场上阵亡的吗？
The King died in battle?
花之城会怎样？
What will happen to Flower City?
我听说他是被自己人杀害的。
I heard that he was killed by one of his own.
怎么可能？谁敢杀害国王？
How could it be? How can anyone kill the King?
我们还要继续对抗尼尔吗？
Are we still going to fight Nyer?
没有王后和国王，我们怎么能赢？
How can we win without a queen and a king?
这是古兰的诅咒造成的吗？
Is this caused by Goran's curse?
王后在出生时就去世了。
The Queen died when she was born.
真不敢相信这竟是花之城的覆灭。
I can't believe this is Flower City's downfall.
也许她不会成为王位继承人。
Maybe she won't be the heir to the throne.
陛下从来都不希望她插手政事。
His Majesty never wanted her to handle politics.
如果她登基，花之城是否就走到了尽头？
If she takes the throne, will it be the end of Flower City?
殿下，
Your Highness,
国王真的打算……
did the King truly mean to...
把王位传给那个受诅咒的女儿吗？
pass his throne to his cursed daughter?
你……
You...
殿下，
Your Highness,
您还好吗？
are you all right?
你在干什么？放开我！
What are you doing? Let me go!
怎么了，尹叔叔？
What's wrong, Uncle Yin?
古兰，
Goran,
我们在国王的帐篷里发现了这把匕首！
we found this dagger in the King's tent!
莫将军，是你用这把匕首杀害了国王吗？
General Mok, did you murder the King with your dagger?
我没有杀他！
I didn't kill him!
殷叔，怎么可能是莫将军呢？
Uncle Yin, How could it be General Mok?
这一定是误会。
It must be a misunderstanding.
古兰，大家都知道莫将军是尼尔人。
Goran, everyone knows General Mok is from Nyer.
我要杀了这个叛徒，
I will kill this traitor and
并在他的葬礼上为我兄长报仇！
avenge my brother at his funeral!
公爵，葬礼可不是篡夺王位的场所！
Duke, a funeral is no place to usurp the throne!
你没资格说话，弑君者！
You're in no position to speak, kingslayer!
把他带走处决！
Take him away and execute him!
是，陛下！
Yes, sire!
放开我！我是清白的！
Let me go! I'm innocent!
——真不敢相信是他。——放开我！
-I can't believe it's him. -Let me go!
国王曾如此信任他。
The King trusted him so.
他该不会有同谋吧？
Could he have accomplices?
你可以骗个小女孩，
You can deceive a little girl,
但骗不了我！
but you can't deceive me!
在调查清楚之前不能杀了他！
You can't kill him before an investigation!
你到底想干什么？
What are you trying to do?
这是我父亲的葬礼。
This is my father's funeral.
让开！
Step aside!
古兰，我正试图
Goran, I am trying to
——为国王报仇！——放开我！
-avenge the King! -Let me go!
放开我，给我让开！
Let me go and back off!
这绝不是我父亲所愿！
This is not what my father would want!
殿下！
Your Highness!
殿下，怎么了？
Your Highness, what's wrong?
健二！
Kenji!
健二……
Kenji...
我叫小妹，你叫什么名字？
My name is Yuri, what's your name?
我叫小鬼。
I'm Gudo.
小鬼，这里是什么地方？
Gudo, what is this place?
我很担心我弟弟。
I'm worried about my little brother.
这里是异世界。
This is Another World.
-我会帮你找到你弟弟的。 -健二！
-I'll help you find your brother. -Kenji!
小鬼，你也是像我一样迷路才来到这里的吗？
Gudo, are you here because you're lost like me?
不，我住在这里。
No, I live here.
那我们一定能找到我弟弟！
Then we'll definitely find my brother!
在我遇到的所有灵魂中……
Among all the souls I've met...
她是第一个没有因恐惧而哭泣，反而展露笑容的人。
she's the first one who smiles instead of crying in fear.
健二！
Kenji!
她经常使用一些我从未听过的词语……
She often uses words I've never heard of...
比如……
Words like...
“思念”、“离别”和“饥饿”。
"longing," "parting" and "hungry."
我完全不知道这些词是什么意思。
I don't know any of those words.
-我觉得…… -健二！
-I think... -Kenji!
-我们必须找到健二…… -健二！
-we have to find Kenji... -Kenji!
否则她就会跟着我转世了。
Before she'll follow me to reincarnation.
另一个世界太大了。
Another World is too big.
根本不可能找到健二。
It's impossible to find Kenji.
我需要休息一下。
I need a break.
小鬼，你不累吗？
Gudo, don't you get tired?
“累”是什么意思？
What is "tired"?
你听到那个声音了吗？
Can you hear that?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我肚子饿了。
My tummy's hungry.
我想家！
I miss my family!
她总是提起她的家人。
She talks about her family all the time.
妈妈做的饭真好吃！
Mommy's food is so yummy!
当她累的时候……
When she's tired...
-健二，你在哪里？-她就会说肚子饿了。
-Kenji, where are you? -she'd say her tummy's hungry.
我想回家吃饭！
I want to go home and eat!
她想找到健二，
She wants to find Kenji,
这样她的家人就能再次一起吃饭了。
so her family can eat together again.
她会在肚子上画个圈圈。
She'd draw a loop on her tummy.
她说那代表“肚子饿了”。
She said it means "her tummy's hungry."
我不记得自己有过家人。
I don't remember having a family.
我该怎么拥有一个“家人”呢？
How do I get a "family"?
为什么由里对
Why does Yuri see
“另一个世界”的看法如此不同？
Another World so differently?
与众不同是一种什么感觉？
How does it feel to be different?
人类世界是什么样的？
What is the human realm like?
公主，您还好吗？
Princess, are you alright?
殿下，您没事吧？
Your Highness, are you OK?
我还活着吗？
Am I still alive?
当然，公主，别傻了。
Of course, Princess, don't be silly.
我父亲怎么样了？
How about my father?
都给我滚！全都滚！
Leave! All of you!
我听说莫克将军想篡夺王位。
I heard General Mok wanted to usurp the throne.
公主，听我说！莫克将军是清白的。
Princess, listen to me! General Mok is innocent.
是敌人的刺客干的！
An enemy assassin did it!
古兰！
Goran!
听着，时间不多了！
Listen, there's not much time!
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
数千名尼尔军队正驻扎在我们城外10公里处。
Thousands of Nyer troops are stationed 10 kilometers outside our city.
据我们的间谍报告，
According to our spy,
莫克将军计划刺杀国王，
General Mok planned to kill the King
并与尼尔勾结。
and colluded with Nyer.
他想让花之城陷落。
He wants Flower City to fall.
公主殿下，请让我处决他！
Princess, let me execute him!
我没有杀国王！
I didn't kill the King!
我父亲教导过我，要给他人留有余地。
My father taught me about giving benefit of the doubt.
我觉得我们应该调查清楚……
I think we should investigate...
现在不是犹豫的时候！
This is no time to hesitate!
我会代表你去参加简报会。
I'll attend the briefing on your behalf.
我们必须反击。
We have to fight back.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
花之城需要一位有能力的领导者。
Flower City needs a capable leader.
希望你能理解。
I hope you understand.
古兰公主。
Princess Goran.
你对我父亲做了什么？
What did you do to my father?
为什么杀了他？
Why did you kill him?
我没有做那种事。
I did no such thing.
那到底是谁干的？
Then who did it?
为什么没人告诉我真相？
Why isn't anyone telling me the truth?
我不在乎你是否与尼尔勾结。
I don't care whether you're colluding with Nyer.
我只想知道我父亲发生了什么。
I just want to know what happened to my father.
如果他去了另一个世界，
If he's gone to Another World,
我该怎么找到他？
how do I find him?
公主殿下，花之城现在需要您坚强起来。
Princess, Flower City needs you to be strong now.
陛下……
His Majesty...
他是自杀的！
he took his own life!
什么？！
What?!
他再也无法忍受伤痛了……
He couldn't bear his injuries any longer...
不可能！绝不可能……
Impossible! That can't be...
返回花城的路途太遥远了。
The journey back to the city was too long.
闭嘴！你在撒谎！
Shut up! You're lying!
他为什么要抛弃花城？
Why would he abandon Flower City?
他不想回来吗？
He didn't want to return?
公主殿下，我不是那个意思！
Princess, that's not what I meant!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
他宁可牺牲生命也要保卫国家！
He would die to defend his nation!
他绝不会自杀……
He'd never kill himself...
——他是在保卫国家…… ——闭嘴！
-He was defending his nation... -Shut up!
你也是。
And you as well.
所以他……希望你能理解。
That's why he... I hope you understand.
骗子！
Liar!
父亲，你到底怎么了？
What happened to you, Father?
现在你们都走了，我孤身一人……
Now that you're both gone, I'm all alone...
我该怎么办？
What am I to do?
是我杀了母亲和父亲吗？！
Did I kill Mother and you?!
花之城不需要我。
I'm not wanted here in Flower City.
我是你们两人的负担，对吧？
I'm a burden to you both, right?
我不该出生在这个世上。
I shouldn't have been born.
父亲绝不会抛弃花之城。
Father would never abandon Flower City.
莫克将军和尹叔叔……
General Mok and Uncle Yin...
他们可能都在说谎……
they could both be lying...
父亲，你会怎么做？
Father, what would you do?
我不是命令你离开了吗？
Didn't I order you to leave?
什么？
What?
嗨，古兰。
Hi, Goran.
1001292
你是什么？是人还是鬼？
What are you? Human or ghost?
1003586
我是小鬼，来自另一个世界。
I am Gudo, I'm from Another World.
1006923
另一个世界……？
Another World...?
1008174
你是灵魂守护者吗？你要带我走吗？
Are you a Soul Keeper? Are you taking me away?
1012762
我曾经是一名灵魂守护者，负责将逝者的灵魂送往转世之地。
I was once a Soul Keeper who took deceased souls to their rebirth.
1017058
但现在我有另一项使命。
But I have another duty now.
1019102
那么……我死了吗？
Then... have I died?
1021062
如果你死了，就不会出现在人类世界了。
You wouldn't be here in the human world if you had died.
1024691
那你为什么在这里？
Then why are you here?
1026484
你要带走我父亲吗？
Are you taking my father away?
1028319
他已经死了。他在另一个世界。
He's dead. He's in Another World.
1030447
那带我去另一个世界！
Then take me to Another World!
1031948
我需要我父亲！
I need my father!
1033366
现在只有他才能拯救花之城。
Only he can save Flower City now.
1035702
我愿意用我的生命来换取他的生命！
I will trade my life for his!
1037495
花之城需要的是他，而不是我。
Flower City needs him, not me.
1040790
为什么？
Why?
1042333
你又没杀过人。
You didn't kill anyone.
1046838
你懂什么？
What do you know?
1049382
你母亲是在分娩时去世的，
Your mother died during childbirth,
1053052
但这并不算你杀了她。
but you didn't kill your mother.
1056306
你为什么在这里？
Why are you here?
1063396
我肚子饿了。
My tummy's hungry.
1064814
什么？
What?
1070028
吃完就走！
Leave after you're done!
1081998
我吃饱了。
I'm full.
1083917
那快滚！
Then beat it!
1085919
我吃饱了！作为回报，我可以帮你一个忙。
I'm full! I can grant you a favor in return.
1090006
我该相信尹叔叔吗？
Should I trust Uncle Yin?
1092008
我不知道。
I don't know.
1093176
那莫克将军是在说谎吗？
Did General Mok lie, then?
1095386
他为什么要这么做？
Why would he do that?
1097013
人间世事难以捉摸，
The human world is unfathomable,
1100892
你只能继续前行。
you can only keep marching on.
1102977
你在说什么？
What are you on about?
1105313
我不明白。
I don't understand.
1107649
我可以带你回到过去的某个时刻。
I can take you back to a moment in the past.
1110568
过去的某个时刻？
A moment in the past?
1114364
你能看到已经发生过的事情。
You can see something that has already happened.
1119452
那带我去父亲去世前的那个时刻。
Then take me to the moment before Father died.
1122163
我需要看看是谁杀了他。
I need to see who murdered him.
1125583
好吧。
All right.
1173381
父亲！
Father!
1176968
古兰！
Goran!
1189898
——就是他！真的是他！——古兰，别走！
-It's him! It's really him! -Goran, don't go!
1194819
小鬼，让她过去。
Gudo, let her through.
1197280
我要一击击杀这个“愤怒”！
I'll kill this Wrath in one blow!
1199741
黑天，等等！
Dark Sky, wait!
1202118
要我说的话，
If you ask me,
1203995
我真搞不懂你为什么磨磨蹭蹭的。
I've no idea why you're dawdling.
1206122
让开。
Out of my way.
1207081
黑天，住手！
Dark Sky, stop!
1209709
这里不是你做主的地方！
You're not in charge here!
1212003
让开！
Step aside!
1215089
父亲！
Father!
1217634
父亲！
Father!
1219260
是他杀了我父亲！
He killed my father!
1220553
-不！ -我定要让他付出代价！
-No! -I'll make him pay!
1225850
放开我！
Let me go!
1231856
古兰！
Goran!
1234233
古兰，振作起来！
Goran, pull yourself together!
1235985
振作起来！
Pull yourself together!
1237320
那并不是全部真相。
That's not the whole truth.
1239739
你必须继续观察。
You have to keep watching.
1241324
醒醒，古兰！
Wake up, Goran!
1242408
小鬼，别再保护那个“愤怒”了！
Gudo, stop protecting that Wrath!
1244285
她没有邪恶之角！她还不是“愤怒”！
She has no evil horn! She's not a Wrath yet!
1246663
我快成功了……
I'm so close...
1248915
快成功什么？
Close to what?
1250291
拔出她的邪恶之种？
Pulling her seed of evil?
1252460
小鬼，她已经看清了真相。
Gudo, she's seen the truth.
1255338
你改变不了任何事！
You can't change anything!
1260009
如果我找到她的结，
If I find her knots,
1261803
我就能拔出那颗邪恶之种！
I can pull the seed of evil!
1264847
我快成功了！
I'm close!
1267225
你无法阻止人类的仇恨！
You can't stop human hatred!
1269894
一旦邪恶之种发芽，就为时已晚！
Once the seed of evil grows, it's too late!
1273606
让开！
Get out of my way!
1275316
三！
Three!
1276442
二！
Two!
1277443
一！
One!
1278820
依我看，那些体内有邪恶之种的人，已经算是“愤怒”了。
If you ask me, those with seeds of evil are Wraths already.
1281739
他们无非是灾难！
They are nothing but disasters!
1283282
他们并非天生如此！
They're not born this way!
1285284
邪恶之种的生长自有其原因！
A seed of evil grows for a reason!
1288246
天女说过，在邪恶之种长出犄角之前……
The Goddess said that before the seed grows horns...
1291958
我还能救她！而你不能伤害她！
I can still help her! And you cannot hurt her!
1295044
就是他……
It's him...
1297046
是他杀了我父亲……
He killed my father...
1299215
他该死……我要报仇！
He deserves to die... I want revenge!
1304178
古兰！
Goran!
1305888
古兰，醒醒！你还没看清全部真相！
Goran, wake up! You haven't seen the whole truth yet!
1309434
让开！
Out of my way!
1315815
这都是因为你是“愤怒”！
This is because you're a Wrath!
1324198
大功告成。
That's a wrap.
1334208
小鬼！
Gudo!
1347138
咦？
Huh?
1361319
我们为什么在这里？
Why are we here?
1363362
我要带你去见天女。
I'm taking you to the Goddess.
1365573
天女？
The Goddess?
1366741
她对“异世界”了如指掌。
She knows everything about Another World.
1369077
她会知道去哪里找你的弟弟。
She will know where to find your brother.
1395978
这些是什么？
What are these?
1400024
当逝去的灵魂转世时，
When deceased souls reincarnate,
1402777
会留下这些绳索。
they leave behind these ropes.
1405571
这些是他们在“异世界”留下的唯一痕迹。
These are the only things they leave behind in Another World.
1410118
为什么绳子上会有结？
Why are there knots on the ropes?
1413204
每个人心中都怀揣着遗憾……
Everyone carries regrets...
1416499
以及未消散的愤怒。
and unresolved rage.
1419544
积累过多就会形成邪恶的种子。
Accumulating too much will form seeds of evil.
1424715
邪恶的种子？
Seeds of evil?
1427135
拥有邪恶种子的人会怎样？
What happens to those with seeds of evil?
1430054
万物皆受平衡法则支配。
Balance rules all things.
1432807
当邪恶的种子潜藏在人的心中……
When a seed of evil hides in a human's heart...
1436394
他们要么变成“愤怒”……
they either become a Wrath...
1439313
要么变成一道光。
or a light ray.
1442358
我们要解开这个结，
We untie the knot
1443734
以尽量减少“愤怒”造成的伤害。
to minimize the damage caused by Wraths.
1448823
让我解释一下，天女！
Let me explain, Goddess!
1450616
小鬼说她还不是“愤怒”，
Gudo said that she isn't a Wrath yet,
1451993
但她的种子已经发芽了。
but her seed's sprouted.
1454203
他对我施展了法力！
He used his powers on me!
1457707
恕我直言，他另有图谋！
No offense, but he has ulterior motives!
1460084
我攻击她只是为了我们大家的利益。
I only attacked her for our own good.
1462003
要我说，我从来不信任人类。
If you ask me, I never trust humans.
1464338
我才不在乎她有没有犄角。
I don't care if she has horns.
1466424
我杀“愤怒”已经多年了，
I've been killing Wraths for years,
1468759
而且我确信古兰迟早会变成“愤怒”！
and I'm sure that Goran will become a Wrath!
1470970
黑天，
Dark Sky,
1472221
你还记得你保护小鬼的承诺吗？
do you remember your promise to protect Gudo?
1476267
我记得，但要我说的话……
I do, but if you ask me...
1479478
黑天，先别说话。
Dark Sky, stop speaking for a minute.
1496621
小鬼。
Gudo.
1498289
你还有机会……
You can still...
1499373
我必须救她。
I have to save her.
1500875
我向她许过诺。
I promised her.
1503044
种子中蕴含的仇恨与愤怒……
The hatred and anger contained in a seed...
1506964
足以改变一个人的本性。
can change one's nature.
1509467
你确定你能做到吗？
Are you sure you can do this?
1510760
我相信她。
I believe in her.
1512720
我会留在人类世界。
I will stay in the human world.
1516682
我能拔出她体内的邪恶之种。
I can pull her seed of evil.
1518601
她的犄角还没长出来，她不会变成“愤怒者”。
Her horns haven't grown, she won't become a Wrath.
1522897
如果你对人类抱有信心，
If you have faith in humanity,
1526275
就必须亲眼见证接下来发生的事。
you must witness what happens next.
1530696
要成功做到这一点，
To pull this off,
1532615
你必须理解人性与时机。
you must understand human nature and timing.
1547046
花之城现在需要一位有能力的领袖……
Flower City needs a capable leader now...
1549757
而那个人绝不会是你！
and it won't be you!
1551634
莫克将军或许杀了国王，
General Mok might have killed the King.
1553594
但真正的凶手是你！
But you are the real murderer!
1576909
别这样，殿下！
Don't do it, Your Highness!
1617116
很久以前，花之城曾有一位受诅咒的公主。
Once upon a time, Flower City had a cursed princess.
1621454
当她得知父亲遇害时，
When she learned that her father was killed,
1624707
她的愤怒迫使“愤怒”将毁灭之力与她分享。
Her anger compelled the Wrath to share his destructive power with her.
1630004
为了复仇，
For the sake of vengeance,
1632298
黑暗在一夜之间笼罩了花之城。
darkness overtook Flower City overnight.
1639513
城中所有的花朵都凋零了。
All the flowers in the city withered.
1645978
她因此被称为“幽灵公主”。
She became known as the "Ghost Princess."
1651192
她失踪后不久，花之城便被征服了。
Soon after she went missing, Flower City was conquered.
1657114
再也没有人见过“幽灵公主”。
No one ever saw the "Ghost Princess" again.
1661202
失去了“幽灵公主”，
Without the "Ghost Princess,"
1663704
花之城变成了麦村。
Flower City became Wheat Village.
1687520
“愤怒”大人……
Wrath, my lord...
1689230
请将您的力量赐予我吧。
please share your power with me.
1691649
时候到了！我们再也等不下去了！
It's time! We can't wait anymore!
1696153
今年的收成惨不忍睹。
This year's harvest has been disastrous.
1698781
记住，为尼尔（Nyer）贡献力量是你们的荣幸。
Remember, it is your privilege to contribute to Nyer.
1701992
你们必须在明天中午之前上交一半的收成。
You must submit half your harvest by noon tomorrow.
1706622
任何人若谎报收成——
Anyone who lies about your harvest,
1709083
这种事以前就发生过——
which has happened before,
1710793
头颅必将落地！
your head will roll!
1735359
在偷懒吗？
Slacking off?
1738112
起来干活！立刻！
Get up and work! Now!
1741407
现在就起来！
Get up now!
1744994
现在就起来，听见了吗？
Get up now, you hear me?
1746370
别装死，你这混蛋！
Don't play dead, you bastard!
1748914
起来！马上！
Get up! Right now!
1751167
将军！
General!
1752042
如果您拿走一半的收成，我们过不了这个冬天！
We won't survive winter if you take half the harvest!
1754670
求您开恩吧！
Please have mercy!
1778986
强，你要去哪儿？是要上山吗？
Keung, where are you going? Headed up the mountain?
1782781
你为什么要去山上？那里都积雪了！
Why are you going up? It's covered in snow!
1785576
我去找食物！
I'm off to find food!
1786452
你是去安魂寺吧？！
You're off to Requiem Temple, aren't you?!
1788037
别去！他们会杀光你全家的！
Don't go! They'll kill your family!
1790998
他们现在就在杀我们啊！
They're already killing us!
1794502
别去，强！
Don't go, Keung!
1795961
那里有可怕的“鬼手”！
There's a scary "ghost hand" there!
1798839
就算你遇到了“怒神”又怎样？
So what if you find a Wrath?
1803219
你会害死我们所有人的。
You'll get us all killed.
1804762
我们不能就这样坐以待毙！
We can't just wait for death!
1806472
我们连温饱都成问题，他们却要拿走一半。
They want half when we barely have enough.
1809141
情况只会越来越糟！
It'll only get worse!
1811101
这三十年里，日子只变得越来越难过了。
Life's only become harder the last 30 years.
1813062
你熬不过这个冬天。
You won't survive the winter.
1816482
我要去安魂寺，
I'll go to Requiem Temple and
1818859
求“怒神”让我变得可怕。
ask the Wrath to make me fearsome.
1820402
那样我就能逼他们……
Then I can force them...
1821487
打开谷仓，把我们的粮食还回来！
to open the barn and return our food!
1824240
段……
Duan...
1825241
强是為了整个小麦村才这么做的。
Keung is doing this for all of Wheat Village.
1829245
你或许没有勇气战斗，但别拦着他。
You may not have the courage to fight, but don't hold him back.
1832581
如果他被抓到，我们全都完了。
If he gets caught, we're all dead.
1835417
你或许不在乎自己的性命，但想想其他人吧！
You may not care about your life, but think of the others!
1848222
我的小女儿。
My little girl.
1851600
妈妈！
Mama!
1852560
爸爸要去哪里？
Where is Papa going?
1853811
我们回家吧。
Let's go home.
1855020
放你爸爸走吧。
Let your father go.
1857690
你不能吃这个！
You can't eat this!
1859608
会肚子疼的。
It'll hurt your tummy.
1873247
“愤怒”可不是闹着玩的！
A Wrath's no joke!
1874582
喂！
Hey!
1875541
回来！
Come back!
1908782
小鬼。
Gudo.
1910242
我闻到这里有“愤怒”的气息。
I can smell a Wrath here.
1938562
天女，你能帮小妹找到她弟弟吗？
Goddess, can you help Yuri find her brother?
1942149
小鬼，你的职责是引导亡灵转世。
Gudo, your job is to guide deceased souls to their reincarnation.
1945986
你为什么要帮她找弟弟？
Why are you helping her find her brother?
1948572
求求你帮帮我！
Please help me!
1959333
他是怎么走丢的？
How did he get lost?
1961877
他四天前失踪了。
He went missing four days ago.
1967800
小鬼，我赐予你
Gudo, I'm granting you
1971595
洞察过去的力量。
the power to see the past.
1974640
这样你就能帮小妹找到她的弟弟了。
You'll be able to help Yuri find her brother.
1978060
不过，你只能看到过去，无法改变它。
However, you can only see the past, you cannot change it.
2084917
愤怒之神，我的主！求您帮帮我们！
Wrath, my lord! Please help us!
2088253
我们别无选择！
We've no other way!
2089713
请把我变成“愤怒”吧！
Please turn me into a Wrath!
2094885
你为什么要成为“愤怒”？
Why would you want to be a Wrath?
2097429
“愤怒”大人！
Wrath, my lord!
2099348
我是小鬼，不是“愤怒”！
I am Gudo, not a Wrath!
2102559
小鬼大人！
Lord Gudo!
2104853
我想成为凶残的“愤怒”！
I want to be a vicious Wrath!
2106980
那样我就能吓唬那些混蛋，救下所有人！
Then I can scare those bastards and save everyone!
2111109
你为什么要救所有人？
Why do you have to save everyone?
2114696
实话实说，大人，
The truth is, my lord,
2116824
我们已经走投无路了。
we're at our wits' end.
2118242
如果我不挺身而出，还有谁会？
If I don't step up, who will?
2120369
为什么非得是“愤怒”不可？
Why must it be a Wrath?
2122079
我必须像“幽灵公主”那样令人畏惧，
I must be as fearsome as the Ghost Princess
2123747
才能吓退那些混蛋。
to scare those bastards.
2125541
“幽灵公主”？
"Ghost Princess"?
2127459
你是说古兰公主吗？
Do you mean Princess Goran?
2129586
是的，我听说她是个“愤怒”，
Yes, I heard that she's a Wrath
2132047
杀光了所有背叛她的人。
who killed all who betrayed her.
2134258
她不是“愤怒”，她只是个女孩。
She was not a Wrath, she was just a girl.
2137970
一个不幸的女孩。
An unfortunate girl.
2141056
幽灵公主！
Ghost Princess!
2143016
你就是“愤怒”！
You're a Wrath!
2145227
公主为什么要这样对待我们？
Why is the Princess doing this to us?
2161201
我在做什么？
What am I doing?
2164162
古兰，如果你愿意，
Goran, if you want,
2167749
我们可以再回去。
we can go back again.
2171169
我想见我父亲。
I want to see my father.
2193400
快走……
Leave...
2195277
在他们赶到之前。
before they get here.
2198530
陛下！
Your Majesty!
2199406
让我留下来。尼尔的军队马上就到。
Let me stay behind. Nyer's army will arrive soon.
2202409
如果您回到花之城，
If you return to Flower City,
2203911
就能得到帮助。
you can get help.
2205537
只有一个办法……
There's only one way...
2208248
用我的尸体拖延时间……
Use my corpse to stall for time...
2210667
我会送你回家的！
I'll get you home!
2212586
陛下，请坚强！
Your Majesty, stay strong!
2214546
古兰正在花之城等你。
Goran is waiting for you in Flower City.
2216840
整个国家都需要你！
The whole nation needs you!
2223972
带古兰走远一点！
Take Goran far away!
2225849
陛下！
Your Majesty!
2227434
医生！
Doctor!
2235734
父亲！
Father!
2237527
父亲！
Father!
2239529
父亲，为什么？
Father, why?
2242991
父亲！
Father!
2249164
别死，父亲！
Don't die, Father!
2257965
古兰。
Goran.
2266598
你已经看清了真相……
You've seen the truth...
2269142
为什么没用？
Why isn't it working?
2278151
走……跑……
Go... ran...
2311560
你母亲在你出生前就病了。
Your mother was ill even before she gave birth to you.
2318066
你的诞生就是我们的奇迹。
Your birth was our miracle.
2321737
被诅咒的是这个地方，不是你。
The cursed one is this place, not you.
2327075
请原谅我，我始终无法从你母亲的离世中走出来，
Forgive me for never getting over your mother,
2330495
也没能好好照顾你。
and failing to take good care of you.
2333957
活下去，
Stay alive,
2336585
这样你才能保护你的族人。
so you can protect your people.
2341923
我知道这些年来你一直很努力……
I know you've tried hard all these years...
2346011
我知道的。
I know that.
2417249
烧掉尸体！马上！
Burn the corpses! Now!
2419626
是，长官！
Yes, sir!
2434266
我把这支箭头带回家好吗？
Should I take this arrowhead home?
2435976
行。
Yeah.
2440272
——别靠近！——走开！
-Don't come closer! -Go away!
2450323
快去躲起来！马上！
Go hide! Right now!
2458415
一定还有别的办法……
There must be another way...
2460709
我得去找尹叔叔，
I need to find Uncle Yin,
2462002
然后我们就能阻止尼尔，拯救花城。
then we'll stop Nyer and save Flower City.
2464754
我们一定能行。
We can do it.
2469718
我们一定能行……
We can do it...
2471428
我需要……我需要……
I need... I need to...
2489654
小鬼，你在干什么？
Gudo, what are you doing?
2491281
你的唯一任务就是拔出她体内的邪恶种子。
Your only mission is to pull her seed of evil.
2493408
但为什么她的生活没有变得更好呢？
But why didn't her life change for the better?
2498538
无论她有没有邪恶种子，
Whether or not she has a seed of evil,
2501124
她的人生都掌握在自己手中……
her life is in her own hands...
2503210
这与你无关。
You have nothing to do with it.
2505629
不知为何，我感觉自己的心碎了。
For some odd reason, I sense my heart shattering.
2515222
小鬼，大人？大人？
Gudo, my lord? My lord?
2520644
哦。
Oh.
2522103
你还在犹豫
Are you still deciding
2524189
要不要把我变成可怕的“愤怒”吗？
whether to turn me into a scary Wrath?
2527234
成为“愤怒”并非你想象的那样。
Being a Wrath is not what you think.
2530237
古兰不是“愤怒”，
Goran was not a Wrath,
2532656
你也不是。
and neither are you.
2534366
“愤怒”只会带来悲剧！
Wraths bring nothing but tragedies!
2537827
你知道“幽灵之手”背后的故事吗？
Do you know the story behind the "Ghost Hand"?
2541539
那一定属于一个凶残的“愤怒”。
It must've belonged to a fierce Wrath.
2544709
那是个走投无路的“愤怒”。
He was a desperate Wrath.
2549172
你知道这是谁的血吗？
Do you know whose blood this is?
2552259
我带你回到300年前，
I'll take you 300 years into the past,
2555220
让你亲眼看看。
so you can see it yourself.
2558431
到时候你再决定是否还想成为“愤怒”。
Then you can decide whether you still want to become a Wrath.
2562727
您说什么都行，大人。
Anything you say, my lord.
2565146
但是……
But...
2566273
但是什么？
But what?
2572112
我肚子饿了。
My tummy's hungry.
2576324
真的吗？
Seriously?
2577158
我身上没带任何食物……
I don't have any food on me...
2583331
等等，这让我想起来了……
Wait, that reminds me...
2585041
说来也怪，我来这儿的路上发现了这个。
Weird enough, I found this on my way here.
2588420
我分你一半。
I'll give you half.
2601558
姜，请记住你是谁……
Keung, please remember who...
2606354
以及你是什么。
and what you are.
2612444
为了村子的安全，
For the village's safety,
2615363
你不能带走祭品。
you cannot take away the sacrifices.
2618491
我女儿不是祭品！
My daughter is not a sacrifice!
2619951
你怎么能杀害自己人？
How can you kill one of your own?
2622037
抓住他！
Catch him!
2624414
想想整个村子，别只顾着自己！
Think of the entire village, not just yourself!
2628168
别杀我们，求求你……
Don't kill us, please...
2634591
爸爸！爸爸变成怪物了！
Papa! Papa has become a monster!
2639512
我们的祈祷被应允了！
Our prayers are answered!
2641723
“愤怒”降临了！
The Wrath is here!
2644601
他会拯救我们脱离这场战火！
He will save us from the battle!
2656196
不，“愤怒”大人，别攻击我们！
No, Lord Wrath, don't attack us!
2658782
救命！
Help!
2662452
卫兵！
Guards!
2663286
哈！活该！
Ha! Serves you right!
2667582
把另一只胳膊也砍掉！
Cut the other arm, too!
2672629
放开我！
Let me go!
2675882
我跑不动了……
I can't run anymore...
2681304
爸爸？爸爸！
Papa? Papa!
2684766
不！
No!
2687352
住手！那是你的女儿！
Stop! That's your daughter!
2689687
到底发生了什么？
What is happening?
2690939
成为“愤怒”并非你们所想的那样。
Being a Wrath is not what you think.
2692816
这种事不会发生在我身上，
This won't happen to me,
2694067
我能控制住自己。
I can control myself.
2696945
“愤怒”无法停止杀戮……
Wraths cannot stop killing...
2699864
直到他们的邪恶犄角被砍掉为止。
until their evil horns are chopped off.
2706246
我认得自己的女儿！
I'll recognize my own daughter!
2708081
这种事绝不会发生在我身上！
This won't happen to me!
2709624
我能救我的家人！
I can save my family!
2719175
那个“愤怒”意志力太薄弱了！
That Wrath had weak willpower!
2721719
这种事绝不会发生在我身上！
It won't happen to me!
2723304
除了我，没人能救我的家人。
No one but me can save my family.
2727684
小鬼大人……
Lord Gudo...
2728977
请把我变成“愤怒”吧……
please turn me into a Wrath...
2730937
我绝不会忘记我的家人！
I won't forget my family!
2735150
小鬼！
Gudo!
2736025
住手！
Stop!
2745076
我早就告诉过你这里有个“愤怒”……
I told you there's a Wrath here...
2759466
段？！
Duan?!
2767515
太慢了！
Too slow!
2780028
我要砍掉你那对邪恶的犄角！该死啦！
I'll chop off your evil horns! Time to die!
2797086
原来你还有两把刷子。
So you've got some moves after all.
2805762
强！
Keung!
2812268
一定还有别的办法！
There must be another way!
2826950
别得意忘形了！
Don't get carried away!
2862860
小鬼，别再睡了，快来帮忙！
Gudo, stop sleeping and come help!
2866531
如果现在不杀掉这个“愤怒”，
If we don't kill this Wrath now,
2868533
另一个世界将遭受苦难。
Another World will suffer.
2870326
如果他的受害者灵魂全都飘向另一个世界，
If his victims' souls all drift to Another World,
2872620
可能会诞生更多的“愤怒”！
it may create more Wraths!
2875748
我有个主意。
I have an idea.
2878126
但我们只有一次机会。
But we only have one shot at it.
2883047
我也能尖叫！
I can scream, too!
2911200
别说我从来没帮过你！
Don't say I never help you!
2949364
安！
Ann!
2959415
安，抓住我的手！
Ann, take my hand!
2977225
卡拉！
Kara!
2979936
抓紧了！
Hold on tight!
2983356
爸爸，帮帮我们！
Help us, Dad!
3059348
段……
Duan...
3071194
——卡拉！——段！
-Kara! -Duan!
3073362
爸爸！
Dad!
3082497
小鬼大人……
Gudo, my lord...
3085583
您是说……
are you telling me that...
3087710
变成“愤怒”也救不了我们吗？
turning into a Wrath won't save us?
3092298
我该怎么办？
What should I do?
3102934
如果小麦村团结起来，我们或许还有一线生机……
If Wheat Village bands together, we may stand a chance...
3107021
姜！
Keung!
3109816
你在哪儿？快回来！
Where are you? Come back!
3112276
让我们团结起来！
Let's get them together!
3114153
夺回属于我们的东西！
We'll reclaim what we deserve!
3117490
小鬼大人……
Lord Gudo...
3120117
我不想变成“愤怒”了，我想保持人形！
I'm done with becoming a Wrath, I want to stay human!
3123955
我想和大家一起夺回我们的食物！
I want to reclaim our food with the others!
3145101
小鬼大人，您在哪里？
Lord Gudo, where are you?
3150857
小鬼大人！
Lord Gudo!
3152441
答应我，不要把我变成“愤怒”！
Promise me you won't turn me into a Wrath!
3161325
你太软弱了，小鬼。
You're weak, Gudo.
3163619
我早就告诉过你，这里不止一个“愤怒”！
I told you there's more than one Wrath out here!
3167164
“愤怒”的数量永远不会超过人类的邪念。
The number of Wraths will never exceed human's evil thoughts.
3172753
他们自食其果。
They reap what they sow.
3174672
真不知道姜会怎样。
I wonder what will happen to Keung.
3177592
小鬼，他不过是个凡人，
Gudo, he's a mere mortal
3180803
终将迎来不可避免的结局。
who will reach an inevitable end.
3182263
我不知道你为什么会……
I don't know why you're being...
3185391
不管这是什么……
whatever this is...
3188060
我们曾立下誓约……
We made a pact...
3190605
为了什么而立下契约？
A pact for what?
3192064
又昏过去了？
Passed out again?
3195526
有我在，你算走运了！
You're lucky you've got me!
3202366
打开谷仓！
Open the barn!
3204243
堕落的渣滓！
Corrupted scum!
3206203
打开谷仓！
Open the barn!
3208080
堕落的渣滓！
Corrupted scum!
3209874
打开谷仓！
Open the barn!
3211751
堕落的渣滓！
Corrupted scum!
3213586
打开谷仓！
Open the barn!
3215463
堕落的渣滓！
Corrupted scum!
3226933
大人，所有农民都来了。
My lord, all the peasants have come.
3231646
退后！
Stay back!
3234190
你们若再向前一步，我就杀了他！
If you take one step forward, I'll kill him!
3240237
放箭！
Fire the arrows.
3245034
求求你们停手！
Please stop!
3246661
你们会杀死自己人！
You'll kill one of your own!
3247954
先救我！
Save me first!
3265221
我砍下自己的手臂就是为了向你们证明，
I cut off my own arm to show you
3269183
这并非“愤怒”的手臂！
that it is not a Wrath's arm!
3271352
它不该属于安魂神殿！
It doesn't belong in Requiem Temple!
3273187
我想向所有人证明……
I want to show everybody...
3275189
今天我失去的不仅仅是一条手臂。
I lost more than an arm today.
3278359
我们还失去了无数挚爱……
We also lost countless loved ones...
3280486
以及那些饿死的人！
and those who died of hunger!
3283155
我们站在你们面前……
We stand before you...
3285032
作为小麦村最后的农夫。
as the last farmers of Wheat Village.
3287994
我们团结一致，为共同的目标……
We're united for a common cause...
3289912
夺回本该属于我们的东西！
to reclaim what is rightfully ours!
3292415
而且我们已做好不惜一切代价的准备！
And we are ready to do whatever it takes!
3296669
如果没人耕种，就没人有饭吃。
If nobody farms, there will be no food for anyone.
3300381
我们都会在地狱里用餐！
We will all dine in hell!
3303551
所以，我最后一次恳求你们……
So, I ask you one last time...
3305511
你们会打开谷仓门吗？！
will you open the barn door?!
3315229
你们这群败类！
You low-lives!
3325906
哼！把谷仓打开！
Hmph! Open the barn!
3363694
当心！
Watch out!
3367990
放我出去！救命！
Let me out! Help!
3371869
救命！放我出去！
Help! Let me out!
3400606
那是什么声音？
What's that noise?
3402608
我去看看。
Let me check.
3405361
是“愤怒”！救命！
It's a Wrath! Help!
3452533
小妹，等我一下！
Yuri, wait for me!
3454034
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
3456036
健二！
Kenji!
3458831
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
3459790
健二！
Kenji!
3464003
小妹！
Yuri!
3466046
小妹！你去哪儿了？
Yuri! Where did you go?
3467798
等我一下！
Wait for me!
3468924
健二！
Kenji!
3470092
小鬼！
Gudo!
3481645
小妹！
Yuri!
3485107
哇哦！
Oh, wow!
3488110
这里真有趣！
This place is so interesting!
3493616
走吧。
Come on.
3496744
你在看什么？快起来！
What are you looking at? Get up!
3505753
我想给你看点东西。
I'd like to show you something.
3538077
所以……我早就死了吗？
So... am I long dead?
3543082
你的身体只是个幻象。
Your body is just an illusion.
3546293
这一切都是幻象吗？
It's all just an illusion?
3549088
那我的死亡也是幻象吗？
So my death is also an illusion?
3552299
死亡只是暂时的状态。
Death is just a temporary state.
3555094
你会转世，重新活过来。
You will reincarnate and live again.
3558764
那我记忆里的人呢？
What about those in my memories?
3561392
只有你的情感是真实的。
Only your feelings are real.
3563519
它们深藏在你的灵魂深处。
They hide deep in your soul.
3566814
就像我想找到我弟弟那样吗？
Like how I want to find my little brother?
3570025
那你呢？
How about you?
3571318
咦？
Huh?
3572736
你也是幻象吗？
Are you an illusion too?
3574738
我是……
I am a...
3588627
天女？！天女？！
Goddess?! Goddess?!
3592965
发生了什么？我会救你的！
What happened? I'll save you!
3595634
我以为我们已经拔除了邪恶之种！
I thought we'd pulled the seed of evil!
3598220
这几千年以来，我依然未能根除人类的仇恨……
All these millennia, I still haven't eradicated human hatred...
3602599
暴行、残忍、怨恨、敌意……
brutality, cruelty, resentment, hostility...
3606937
“愤怒者”的邪恶已吞噬了人类，
The Wraths' evil have consumed humanity,
3609857
因此“异世界”必须承受这一切。
so Another World must endure this.
3612651
万物皆不可测，但它们只能继续前行。
All things are unfathomable, but they can only keep marching on.
3616947
天女，没时间讲什么禅了！
Goddess, there's no time to talk zen!
3620242
直奔主题！我们该怎么把你救出来？
Get to the point! How do we get you out?
3623996
先解开小鬼的结，
Untie Gudo's knot first,
3626332
奇迹就在前方。
a miracle awaits.
3637676
小鬼，你的结在哪里？
Gudo, where is your knot?
3639511
交出来！
Give it to me!
3641013
我的结？
My knot?
3643265
怎么回事？你的结是比喻吗？
What now? Is your knot metaphorical?
3647227
我们现在该怎么办？
What should we do now?
3648979
我不会解结，只会杀“愤怒者”。
I don't know how to untie knots, I only know how to kill Wraths.
3652941
“另一个世界”到底怎么了？
What is happening to Another World?
3654401
这些是逝去灵魂留下的红绳。
These are the red ropes left by deceased souls.
3657363
当强村的村民们战斗时，
When Keung's villagers fought,
3659823
有人变成了“愤怒”。
someone became a Wrath.
3661367
大家都死了！
Everyone died!
3662868
强村的人呢？
How about Keung?
3664119
他们成功了吗？
Did they succeed?
3665329
如果成功了，“另一个世界”就不会陷入困境了！
If they did, Another World wouldn't be in trouble!
3668123
那天女呢？
And the Goddess?
3669625
她被绳索缠住了，我无法斩断它们。
She's tangled up in the ropes, I can't sever them.
3672878
她说我必须解开你的结。
She said I must untie your knot.
3675339
小鬼，快想办法！
Gudo, think!
3677841
我知道这对你来说很奇怪，毕竟你不是人类。
I know it is weird for you since you are not a human.
3681428
但你有没有解开过绳结呢？
But is it possible that you have untied knots?
3710249
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
3726181
小鬼……
Gudo...
3727724
我会和你一起去的。
I will go with you.
3731937
好！
Okay!
3759840
求求你别拿走！
Please don't take it!
3762050
还给我！
Give it back!
3764887
滚开！
Beat it!
3807346
健二……
Kenji...
3809181
健二，张开嘴……
Kenji, open your mouth...
3812809
你必须喝下去。
You have to drink.
3814603
健二……
Kenji...
3818899
健二……
Kenji...
3821735
健二……
Kenji...
3826365
健二……
Kenji...
3837834
走开！
Go away!
3839795
我们没有食物。
We don't have any food.
3891388
健二。
Kenji.
3894474
健二在哪里？
Where's Kenji?
3933764
他的生命延长了你的生命。
His life extended your life.
3937017
人类肚子饿了就必须吃饭。
Humans must eat when their tummies are hungry.
3940103
你不必难过。
You don't have to be sad.
3943273
但他是我弟弟啊！
But he's my brother!
3952824
小妹！
Yuri!
3993907
这是什么？
What is this?
3997661
小妹！
Yuri!
4008130
好烫啊！
It's so hot!
4013093
你是小妹，肚子饿的时候你就是这样做的！
You're Yuri, you do this when your tummy's hungry!
4017514
你是小妹，
You're Yuri,
4022060
你妈妈可是个烹饪高手！
your mother is a great cook!
4025105
小妹！
Yuri!
4027107
你是小妹，你还得找到你弟弟并转世！
You're Yuri, you still have to find your brother and reincarnate!
4033780
醒醒！
Wake up!
4065437
小鬼，我这是怎么了？
Gudo, what is happening to me?
4069775
我不知道。
I don't know.
4071902
不过你现在没事了……
But you are fine now...
4075322
小妹，你的邪恶种子
Yuri, your seed of evil
4077699
终究在“另一个世界”发芽了。
has sprouted in Another World after all.
4083079
看到真相后，
After seeing the truth,
4086333
我以为她会转世。
I thought she would reincarnate.
4088168
没想到，这反而触发了她向“愤怒”的蜕变。
Instead, it triggered her transformation into a Wrath.
4090712
天女，小妹不是“愤怒”。
Goddess, Yuri is not a Wrath.
4093215
她已经见到了弟弟。
She's seen her brother.
4094966
我可以带她去转世。
I can take her to reincarnation.
4097135
小鬼，你不明白。
Gudo, you don't understand.
4099346
她的邪恶种子已经发芽了。
Her seed of evil has sprouted.
4101431
带着邪恶种子的灵魂无法转世。
Souls with seeds of evil cannot reincarnate.
4103892
不！我必须帮她转世！
No! I must help her reincarnate!
4107479
小鬼……我们该怎么办？
Gudo... what should we do?
4110148
我会带你去下一世！
I'll take you to your next life!
4112317
你还能再见到弟弟！
You'll see your brother again!
4114528
她不能留在异世界，也无法转世……
She cannot stay in Another World, and she cannot reincarnate...
4119449
她只能留在这里……
she has to stay here...
4121493
化作尘土……
and crumble into dust...
4136216
小妹！
Yuri!
4138009
天女！
Goddess!
4139553
求求您帮帮她！
Please help her!
4158238
小鬼！
Gudo!
4221343
我们现在该怎么办？
What should we do now?
4239778
哇啊……！哇啊……！
Waah...! Waah...!
4244240
小鬼，你在做什么？
What are you doing, Gudo?
4247285
我正试着像你一样哭呢。
I'm trying to cry like you.
4250372
我好害怕再也见不到我的家人
I'm scared I'll never see my family
4253875
和健二了……
and Kenji again...
4256753
一想到再也见不到你……
When I think of never seeing you again...
4259547
我就开始明白了。
I begin to understand.
4261675
哇啊……！哇啊……！
Waah...! Waah...!
4286950
健……二……
Ken... ji...
4300463
他们还在这里吗？
Are they still here?
4302090
不在了。
No.
4304509
这里发生了什么？
What happened here?
4338460
大地之母……
Mother Earth...
4341129
为什么人们心中会有邪恶的种子？
why do people have seeds of evil?
4346426
这一切都始于智慧……
It all started with wisdom...
4347927
当人类开始区分善恶之时。
when human beings began to differentiate good from evil.
4352599
所以人类是邪恶种子的源头吗？
So human beings are the source of the seed of evil?
4357479
他们想要利用破坏的力量……
They wanted to use destructive powers...
4360356
来纠正他们眼中的一切错误。
to right all that they saw as wrong.
4362484
那么我们该如何消除他们心中的邪恶种子呢？
Then how do we remove their seeds of evil?
4367030
当因缘消散时，万物便会瓦解。
All things come apart when causes and conditions dissipate.
4370075
小妹想要转世，但她体内藏着一颗邪恶的种子。
Yuri wants to reincarnate, but she has a seed of evil in her.
4375538
带着邪恶种子转世的灵魂……
Souls reincarnating with seeds of evil...
4378416
必须经历一千年。
must live through a millennium.
4381920
无论转世多少次，
No matter how many times they reincarnate,
4385673
都会一直带着它吗？
they still carry it?
4401356
小鬼，
Gudo,
4402524
你听到了大地之母的话。
you heard what Mother Earth said.
4405610
如果小妹的第二只邪恶之角长出来，
If Yuri's second evil horn grows,
4409280
她的力量不仅会威胁人类世界……
her power will threaten not only the human world...
4413034
还会威胁另一个世界。
but also Another World.
4420041
但如果我从她每一世中拔除那颗邪恶的种子，
But if I pull the seeds of evil from each of her lives,
4423461
一千年后她就能转世为普通人。
she can reincarnate into a normal person after a millennium.
4427757
人会改变的。小妹已经长出一只邪恶之角了。
People change. Yuri already has one evil horn.
4432554
你确定她的种子在
You're sure her seed won't sprout
4435181
接下来的这一千年里不会发芽吗？
over the next millennium?
4437517
我会一直陪在她身边！
I will stay with her!
4439727
她每转世一次，
Every time she reincarnates,
4442063
那颗种子的力量就会更强。
her seed grows more powerful.
4444065
不过是一千年而已。
It's only 1,000 years.
4445775
这绝非易事。
It will not be easy.
4447944
我能做到的。
I can do it.
4449154
如果小妹变成了“愤怒”，
If Yuri turns into a Wrath,
4452907
你和小妹都会化为尘土……
both you and Yuri will crumble into dust...
4456619
我绝不会放弃！
I won't give up!
4459873
小鬼，你确定要这么做吗？
Are you sure you want to do this, Gudo?
4471926
我对她有信心。
I have faith in her.
4474095
小妹，如果你想救你的弟弟，
Yuri, if you want to save your little brother,
4478224
就必须忘记他。
you must forget him.
4480852
如果我放他走，
If I let him go,
4482061
他就能得救吗？
he'll be saved?
4487817
小妹，
Yuri,
4489694
要想再见到他，
to see him again,
4491279
你必须转世。
you have to reincarnate.
4493907
要转世，
To reincarnate,
4495700
你就必须忘记他。
you have to forget him.
4498161
所以，转世是再见到他的唯一办法吗？
So, rebirth is the only way to see him again?
4508463
我想转世！我要转世！
I want to be reborn! I want a rebirth!
4536658
小鬼，
Gudo,
4537909
记住你那千年的承诺。
remember your promise of a thousand years.
4541913
我会的！
I will!
4613693
这些是什么？
What are these?
4615611
你的记忆。
Your memories.
4617947
我好像没见过这些……
I don't think I've seen these...
4620575
记忆太沉重了。
Memories are too heavy.
4622410
你必须把它们留在这里。
You have to leave them here.
4625246
否则……
Otherwise...
4627081
你就无法渡过。
you cannot cross over.
4633671
一旦渡过……
Once you cross...
4635131
你就能再见到你的弟弟了。
you'll see your brother again.
4639010
好！
Okay!
4699987
等我。
Wait for me.
4732520
我会忘记你吗？
Will I forget you?
4738359
小妹，
Yuri,
4739944
当你穿过瀑布之后，
after you pass the waterfall,
4741904
你将进入下一世。
you will enter your next life.
4743781
那你呢？
How about you?
4746659
我保证……
I promise...
4748828
无论你去哪里，
no matter where you go,
4750079
我都会找到你。
I'll find you.
4764677
我会记得你吗？
Will I remember you?
4766721
我该怎么认出你？
How will I recognize you?
4804675
小鬼！
Gudo!
4810806
在下一千年里，
In the next millennium,
4813768
无论你走到哪里……
no matter where you go...
4816062
我都会找到你。
I'll find you.
4818564
我保证……
I promise...
4820316
我一定会找到你。
I will find you.
4968923
所以，古兰和姜
So, both Goran and Keung
4970591
都是小妹的转世。
are Yuri's reincarnations.
4973010
而且在他们之前还有其他人。
And there were others before them.
4975429
我记得他们。所以，已经过去了一千年……
I remember them. So, a millennium has passed...
4978724
灵魂守护者不能如此频繁地进入人间。
Soul Keepers cannot enter the human world so many times.
4981602
这就是你如此虚弱的原因……
That's why you are so weak...
4983562
我们有过约定。
We have a pact.
4986524
但她不认得你……
But she doesn't recognize you...
4989402
我认得她，我们有过约定！
I recognize her, we have a pact!
4992446
如果问我的话，
If you ask me,
4993739
我会说你在浪费时间。
I'd say you're wasting your time.
4995991
没冒犯的意思，但我另有目的。
No offense, but I have an ulterior motive.
4998494
哈！你这个模仿者！
Ha! You copycat!
5000746
我会找到她的。
I will find her.
5002248
这是她在这千年里的最后一次转世。
This is her last life in the millennium.
5006293
我终于明白了！她就是你的“结”！
I get it now! She's your "knot"!
5009255
但如果你这次死了呢？
But what if you die this time?
5011799
值得吗？
Is it worth it?
5013551
你会化为尘土。
You'll crumble into dust.
5016220
我向天女发誓要保护你。
I promised Goddess to protect you.
5018597
我头好痛，明明我根本没有头！
My head hurts, and I'm headless!
5023018
如果人类可以转世，
If humans can reincarnate,
5024186
而我化为尘土，
and if I crumble into dust,
5027690
我的“结”会回到米山吗？
will my knot return to Mount Mi?
5030401
要我說的話，
If you ask me,
5031652
化为尘土就意味着什么都不剩了。
I'd say crumbling into dust means nothing's left.
5036407
如果小妹变成了“愤怒”，
If Yuri turns into a Wrath,
5038534
我该怎么办？
what should I do?
5041996
你会阻止她的！
You'll stop her!
5045249
但先警告你，如果她变成了“愤怒”，
But fair warning, if she turns into a Wrath,
5048419
我必须杀了她。
I have to kill her.
5059305
我相信她不会变成“愤怒”的。
I have faith that she won't turn into a Wrath.
5063017
那我们走吧。
Then let's go.
5064852
你可是立过誓约的！
You have a pact!
5067938
而且我必须拯救天女。
And I have to save Goddess.
5079492
吃点东西吧，不然你会饿死的！
Eat something, or you'll starve!
5081827
但我只喜欢你做的饭。
But I only like your cooking.
5084663
你只是拿我的食物喂你的猫罢了。
You're just using my food to feed your cat.
5086999
走吧！回去工作！
Let's go! Back to work!
5098552
看，烟囱里冒出来的东西看起来像我的头发。
Look, the stuff from the chimneys look like my hair.
5107978
我不是让你在“另一个世界”好好休息一下了吗？
I told you to get some rest in Another World.
5113651
你没必要一直待在这里
You don't need to be here all the time
5116278
把自己累垮。
and exhaust yourself.
5118906
我没事，我想看看英工作时的样子。
I'll be fine, I want to see Ying at work.
5124745
有什么好看的？
What's there to see?
5126330
她们只是站在那里织布而已。
They just stand there and weave.
5129166
可是……
But...
5131710
行吧，等会儿我带你去那里。
Fine, I'll take you there later.
5135464
我闻到那边有“愤怒”的气息，黑天……
I can smell a Wrath over there, Dark Sky...
5140052
你真是没用！
You're so useless!
5143013
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
5144557
你的活儿没一样合格的！
None of your work passes muster!
5147059
你把机器弄坏了！
You're breaking the machine!
5148894
做不到就滚开！
Scram if you're not up to it!
5150479
别拖我们后腿！
Don't drag us down!
5152147
马克，你这是怎么了？
Mark, what's with you?
5154525
主管不在
The supervisor's absence
5155526
不代表你就能当家作主！
doesn't mean you're in charge!
5156861
总是你们两个！
It's always you two!
5158404
都是因为你们，我们的餐券才被削减了！
You're why they cut our meal tickets!
5160030
听见了吗？
You hear that?
5162283
别理他。
Don't listen to him.
5163701
我们会修好的，管好你自己的事！
We'll fix them, mind your own business!
5165870
娜娜……
Nana...
5166912
没错，你们无能跟我们没关系！
Exactly, your incompetence shouldn't be our business!
5169915
但我们全都因此挨饿！
But we all starve because of it!
5172293
说得对！
That's right!
5173168
别拖我们后腿了！
Stop dragging us down!
5174962
他们能去哪儿？
Where can they go?
5176922
他们跟我们一样……
They are just like us...
5178549
被卖到这里当童工的。
sold to be child workers here.
5179717
哈迪，你想当英雄吗？
Hardy, you wanna be a hero?
5181552
搞完了吗？
Are you done?
5182636
——你们这群恶霸！——娜娜，别……
-You bullies! -Nana, stop...
5184597
你们这群臭孤儿！
You stinking orphans!
5186557
你打我了！
You hit me!
5189393
住手！
Stop!
5193272
娜娜，别理他们……
Nana, just ignore them...
5196025
说完了吗？别管我们！
Are you done? Leave us alone!
5200321
这都是你的错！
It's all because of you!
5201614
住手！住手！
Stop! Stop!
5202656
别伤害我姐姐！
Don't hurt my sister!
5213125
住手，马克！
Stop, Mark!
5216045
退后！
Back off!
5230976
娜娜！
Nana!
5231852
英，别动！
Ying, stay where you are!
5235230
退后！
Stay back!
5237942
有“愤怒”组织？我应该知道。
There's a Wrath? I would know.
5239944
那只是英的工厂。
It's just Ying's factory.
5241403
去看看吧。
Go take a look.
5242988
英！
Ying!
5255668
娜娜！
Nana!
5257920
好烫啊！
That's so hot!
5262049
娜娜！
Nana!
5265302
娜娜！
Nana!
5266804
这边！小心点！
This way! Be careful!
5311056
娜娜？
Nana?
5328157
我姐姐为什么会死？
Why did my sister die?
5332202
是因为我吗？
Is it because of me?
5335330
都是我的错！
It's because of me!
5340294
是我杀了我的姐姐！
I killed my sister!
5361982
着火了！救命！
Fire! Help!
5366153
英！
Ying!
5367738
情况突然变得很严重！
That escalated quickly!
5369323
英，你在哪儿？
Where are you, Ying?
5371784
英！
Ying!
5375913
英，你在干什么？快走！
Ying, what are you doing? Let's go!
5379833
这里很危险。
It's dangerous here.
5388425
英！
Ying!
5390052
你还记得这个吗？
Do you remember this?
5392346
别变成“愤怒”！
Don't turn into a Wrath!
5394264
你的名字是小妹！你还记得吗？
Your name is Yuri! Do you remember?
5396809
我是小鬼！你还记得吗？
I'm Gudo! Do you remember?
5400896
我们离成功这么近了！醒醒！
We're so close! Wake up!
5405150
醒醒，小妹！
Wake up, Yuri!
5407986
我答应过我们会一起找到你的弟弟！
I promised we'd find your brother together!
5411824
健二……
Kenji...
5416036
小妹，你还记得我吗？
Do you remember me, Yuri?
5424419
对不起，小鬼！
I'm sorry, Gudo!
5425504
她已经不是小妹了！
She's no longer Yuri!
5441436
小妹，不要！
Yuri, no!
5448026
小妹！
Yuri!
5450237
小妹！
Yuri!
5464293
喂，你听见了吗？
Hey, can you hear that?
5468130
看……
Look...
5469173
那是……
that's...
5476638
小妹，你必须停下来！
Yuri, you have to stop!
5482978
黑天，不要……
Dark Sky, no...
5485981
我们还有机会……
We still have a chance...
5491236
停下，小妹！
Stop, Yuri!
5506877
别逼我！
Don't force my hand!
5514885
不……不……
Na... na...
5525145
我真的会杀了你！
I really will kill you!
5542829
清醒点！
Snap out of it!
5545374
看来就这样了！
I guess that's it!
5551004
不，黑天！她还是人类！
No, Dark Sky! She's still human!
5554174
让开！
Get out of my way!
5566687
小鬼，你为什么要拦我？！
Gudo, why'd you stop me?!
5568772
如果现在不杀死“愤怒”，
If we don't kill the Wrath now,
5571066
人类世界和异世界都会被毁灭！
both the human world and Another World will be destroyed!
5573819
我们错失良机了！
We missed our chance!
5575529
因为你天真地以为能救她！
Because you were naïve enough to think you can save her!
5578448
你把我的剑弄断了！难道我要徒手和她战斗吗？
You broke my sword! Should I fight her with my bare hands?
5581994
睁大眼睛好好看看！
Open your eyes and take a look!
5583829
她看起来像人类吗？
Does she look like a human to you?
5585789
她或许看起来像小妹或英，
She may look like Yuri or Ying,
5587874
但她现在已经是“愤怒”了。
but she's a Wrath now.
5589876
如果她的邪恶犄角被封印，
If her evil horns are sealed,
5591253
一切就都完了！
it's all over!
5592713
不只是这里！“异世界”和“天女”也会完蛋！
Not just this place! Another World and Goddess, too!
5595424
算了！
Forget this!
5597676
小妹……别变成“愤怒”……
Yuri... Don't turn into a Wrath...
5602597
你还记得吗？
Do you remember?
5608353
我知道你想干什么！
I know what you are trying to do!
5610355
住手！
Stop!
5620866
你这副骨架，怎么这么沉？
Why are you so heavy, you bag of bones?
5635380
把那对邪恶的犄角砍下来！
Let's chop those evil horns off!
5644348
黑天……
Dark Sky...
5653732
小鬼！如果你能回到异世界见到天女……
Gudo! If you make it back to Another World and see Goddess...
5657652
一定要告诉她……
you have to tell her...
5659196
我已经竭尽全力保护你了！
I did my best to protect you!
5688183
对不起，小鬼。
Sorry, Gudo.
5689559
我现在必须杀了她！
I have to kill her now!
5703490
这家伙真难对付。
This thing's a tough one.
5752372
小妹……
Yuri...
5755792
别这样！
Don't do this!
5764259
我是小鬼……
I'm Gudo...
5770307
你还记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
5773477
这一切都是值得的。
It's worth it.
5778356
这千年……全都值得了！
These thousand years... was all worth it!
5792245
我是谁？
Who am I?
5796708
小妹。
Yuri.
5799085
小妹？
Yuri?
5804132
我是谁？
Who am I?
5808386
穿过瀑布后，你将进入下一世。
After you pass the waterfall, you will enter your next life.
5812557
那你呢？
How about you?
5813975
我保证，无论你去哪里，我都会找到你。
I promise, wherever you go, I will find you.
5817771
我会记得你吗？
Will I remember you?
5822943
你叫小妹，死在了一座山上。
Your name is Yuri, you died on a mountain.
5827697
那时你正在寻找你的弟弟。
You were looking for your little brother then.
5834246
我的弟弟……
My little brother...
5844839
我的弟弟……
My little brother...
5846758
我吃了……
I ate...
5851846
我……
I...
5852889
我吃了我的弟弟？
I ate my little brother?
5856101
你必须原谅自己！
You have to forgive yourself!
5858562
只有这样，我才能消除你心中的邪恶种子。
That's the only way I can take away your seed of evil.
5863900
小妹，别自责了！
Yuri, don't blame yourself!
5867779
那是命运的安排！
They're acts of fate!
5870365
我记起来了！我杀了那么多人！
I remember now! I killed so many people!
5875453
那么多人因为我而死去！
So many died because of me!
5878248
我杀了那么多人！
I killed so many people!
5880709
我真是个恶人！
I'm an evil person!
5884754
不是你把他们送上死路！
You didn't send them to their deaths!
5890969
只是你没能救下他们罢了！
You just couldn't save them!
5894973
我不配得到宽恕……
I'm not worthy of forgiveness...
5908820
小妹！
Yuri!
5910405
看看你的双手，你正抓着谁？
Look at your hands, who are you grabbing?
5914284
看看你抓着的是谁！
Look at who you're grabbing!
5919831
小妹！
Yuri!
5921291
看看你抓着的是谁！
Look at who you're grabbing!
5937474
健二？
Kenji?
5961081
英救了你……是我在这辈子救了你吗？
Ying saved you... I saved you in this life?
5971549
我有资格给予救赎吗？
Am I qualified to offer salvation?
5981393
任何人都能给予救赎，
Anyone can offer salvation,
5987273
你只需要相信时间，相信自己。
you just need to have faith in time and yourself.
5992612
你心中有仁慈，只是把它忘了。
You have kindness in you, you just forgot about it.
6070064
“愤怒”的气息消失了……
The aura of the Wrath is gone...
6096341
英！英……
Ying! Ying...
6106059
英！你没事吧？
Ying! Are you all right?
6112524
我认出你了……
I recognize you...
6115902
你还记得我吗？没错，是我，哈迪！
You remember me? That's right, it's Hardy!
6125912
我已经找了你一千年了！
I've been looking for you for a thousand years!
6135380
小鬼，喂……
Gudo, hey...
6139676
古……小鬼……
Gu... Gudo...
6145974
小鬼，坚持住！
Gudo, hang in there!
6158862
没时间了！
There's no time!
6162740
已经太迟了！
It's too late!
6180842
小鬼，
Gudo,
6182927
异世界的所有结都已解开。
all the knots in Another World have been untied.
6187056
天女。
Goddess.
6189058
这意味着我很快就会化为尘土了吗？
Does that mean I'll soon crumble into dust?
6192812
小鬼……
Gudo...
6195315
小鬼……
Gudo...
6200570
小鬼……
Gudo...
6201738
我们曾立下誓约。
we made a pact.
6203698
我从未忘记你。
I didn't forget about you.
6214334
你现在会哭了！
You know how to cry now!
6217211
天女，小妹能重新成为普通人吗？
Goddess, can Yuri be a normal person again?
6221257
她现在可以转世了吗？
Can she reincarnate now?
6223176
是的。
Yes.
6226429
我现在既不能待在人间……
I can't be in the human world...
6229849
也不能待在异世界了。
nor Another World now.
6233227
一切都结束了。
It's all over.
6237857
还有另一种方法。
There's another way.
6240109
你可以转世，成为一个普通人。
You can reincarnate and become a human being.
6254791
我必须忘记……
Do I have to forget...
6265093
过去的一千年吗？
the past millennium?
6283653
原来离别的悲伤是这种感觉……
So this is how the sorrow of parting feels...
6294080
我现在明白了。
I get it now.
6369864
另一个世界
ANOTHER WORLD
6391385
如果问我的话，我会说你在浪费时间。
If you ask me, I'd say you're wasting your time.
6398601
没关系，我会从这里守护着他。
It's okay, I'll watch over him from here.